Finding Aid for the The Nelson and Marion Fuson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Organizations and Community Activities - Poor People's Campaign American Friends Service Committee
  - Mass Meeting Announcement Mail Appeal "Poor People's Campaign for Jobs and Income"
  - Financial Report of Interfaith Poor People's Campaign
- Organizations and Community Activities - Committee on Racial Equality (CORE)
  - Letter to Civic and Social Minded Persons and Organizations
  - Amended Constitution of the Congress of Racial Equality CORE Action Discipline
- Organizations and Community Activities - Tennessee A & I Student Demonstrations
  - Resolutions adopted by American Association of University Professsors
  - Letter to Etta Simpson from University Discipline Committee
  - Handwritten note to Marian Fuson
  - List of People to Help get Signatures for Petition
  - Chronology Concerning A & I Student Demonstrations
  - Handwritten notes of talk with Carolyn Reid
  - Summary of Citizens Committee on A & I Students Decisions made following Conference with Commissioner of Education Morgan, including Correspondence
  - Letters to Faculty and Administration
  - Statement of Meeting of State Board of Education
  - Minutes of Meetings
  - N. Fuson's Notes from meeting with Commissioner Morgan
  - Petition for Reinstatement of students at Tennessee A & I
  - Minutes of Executive Committee
  - Letter to Kelly Miller Smith from Avon Williams Re:Suspension of College students participating in Freedom Rides
  - Memo from N. Fuson
  - Letter from Leo Lillard of Student Non-Violent Movement
- Articles, Pamphlets, and Brochures about Human Relations
  - Bergstrom, Herbert and Glenn Everett. "The FEPC Faces a Crisis: Philadelphia Strike"
  - The Forerunner Newsletter, Racial Brotherhood Issue 1944 Petition: Statement on the Race Relations Crisis
  - Y-Teen College fro Y.W. Knowledge program
  - White, Walter. "Why I Remain a Negro," Saturday Review of Literature. Reprint
  - Miscellaneous articles: "Guam Crime Laid to 3 Negro GI's," "3 Men Named as Farnsworth Slayers in Guam," "3 Negro GI's Held in Guam Murder, One from Frederick" New York Times
  - Sprigle, Ray. "In the Land of Jim Crow" Pittsburgh Post Gazette
  - Whitman, Hazel. "The Condition of Farm Workers in 1948" Report to Board of Directors of National Sharecroppers Fund, Inc.
  - "Slave Labor Issue" in Workers Defense Bulletin
  - Pringle, Henry F. and Katherine "The Color Line in Medicine" Saturday Evening Post.(1/24/48) reprinted by The Committee of 100
  - "Statement on Interracial Marriage," Congregational Christian Churches
  - Announcement of meeting: "Call to Conference to End Segregation and Discrimination"
  - Poston, Ted. "On Appeal in the Supreme Court," The Survey
  - "The Social Order Committees" Philadelphia Yearly Meetings of the Society of Friends
  - Articles taken from New York Times "South Exhibit Asks Negro Art, Bans Race," and "Admits White Student"
  - Article about Ralph Bunche, "National Affairs"
  - Address: Bunche, Ralph J. "Free Peoples in a Free Society," The Committee of 10
  - Whitman, Howard. "Washington-Disgrace to the Nation," Woman's Home Companion
  - Dickerson, Mahala Ashley. "Negro Lawyer in the South, Part I" Friends Intelligencer
  - "Parish Welcomes Negro at Pastor" New York Times
  - Foley, Albert. "Black Face Minstrels: 10 Reasons Why They're Not so Funny" Catholic Interracialist
  - "Enforcing Racial Segregation" Letters to the Times, New York Times
  - "Working Together" American Friends Service Committee
  - Schomburg, Arthur A. What is the Schomburg Collection?
  - Miscellaneous Articles: "Citizens Council Behind Tchula 'Protest' Meeting," "The Reaction," "Edlers Ask Minister to Resign in Durant," "Angry Citizens Ask White Men to Leave," "Accused Holmes Men Deny 'Red' Charges; Claim They not Listed as Subversing," "Cox, Minter 'Bewildered' at Requests of Citizens," "Memo to Some Holmes Countians" Delta-Democrat Times (9/30/55)
  - DuBois, Rachel Davis. "Keep the Channels Open" Friends Intelligencer
  - Cobb, W. Montague. "The Strait Gate," Journal of the National Medical Association. Reprint.
  - "Cox and Minter Case" People in Mississippi: 2 articles: Miller, William Lee. "Trial by Tape Recorder," Halberstam, David. "A County Divided Against Itself"
  - Changing Patterns in the New South Table of Contents
  - Martin Luther King and the Montgomery Story Comic Book
  - Bulletin: The Fellowship of Reconciliation
  - Political Advertisement: H.J. Ryan for Congress "To all Voters of Nashville and Davidson County"
  - Rustin, Bayard. "Report on Montgomery, Alabama" War Resisters League
  - Nashville Community Relations Conference Invitation
  - Huddleston, Trevor. "The Deep South and South Africa," Presbyterian Life
  - "The Churches Speak" Crusade for Freedom Panel Discussion, Grade 2 "Free Schools in a Free America"; "What the Churches Have Said on the Supreme Court Decision on Segregation in the South" United Church Women publication
  - Miller, Alexander F. "Violence: It Need not Happen"
  - Highlander Report: 27th Annual Report of Highlander Folk School, Monteagle, TN, 10/58-9/59
  - Maund, Alfred. The Untouchables: The Meaning of Segregation in Hospitals
  - "Dear Alumni," Fisk News, 1960 Spring
  - "Report on Nashville 1960; its Problems and Possiblities"
  - "Sit-ins Unseat Jim Crow," Fisk University Forums
  - O'Donovan, Patrick. "Negros Revolt Against the 'Vertical Plan'"
  - King, Martin Luther. "Letter from Birmingham City Jail," Circulated by American Friends Service Committee
  - Daily News Brief Newsletter
  - Highlights from Highlander workshop
  - Blanchard, Dallas, Ed. Prospectus Weekly Newsletter of Vanderbilt Divinity School
  - Article: "Picketers Won't Be Sidelined"
  - Articles in The Southern Patriot
  - Westfeldt, Wallace. "Settling a Sit-in," NCRC (2 Copies)
  - Moore, Julia, "From Jubilee Bell Tower" Fisk News, 1960 Summer
  - Mail Order Form: The Commission on Social Action of Reform Judaism
  - Notice from NCLC: "Wilson-Quick Uses Violence on Negroes Seeking to be Served"
  - Brochure on the history of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference
  - News Release: "Jailed Sit-ins Given Solitary," Student Non-Violent Movement
  - Gunter, Laurie M. "The Effects of Segregation on Nursing Students" Nursing Outlook
  - Information Sheet: "A Call for Help" Operation Freedom
  - Brochure: "St. Louis Public Accomodations Policy," St. Louis Council on Human Relations 12/61 NAACP Newsletter Vol. 1, No. 6
  - Letter to all Pastors from Operation Open City
  - Report on Nashville 1961: Human Relations Inventory by Nashville Community Relations Conference
  - Homes and Community Brochure by American Friends Service Committee Community Relations Program
  - Cooke, Alistair. "Negroes Take a Seat."
  - Zinn, Howard. "Albany: A Study in National Responsibility," Southern Regional Council
  - Face Sheet on Clyde Kennard's Imprisonment in Mississippi
  - Report of the City-Wide Committee for Equal Services, Knoxville, TN
  - Golden, Harry. "The American Dream."Johns Hopkins Magazine Jobs and Color: Negro Employment in Tennessee State Government. Report of Nashville Community Conference on Employment Opportunity
  - Wechsler, James A. "The American Saga," New York Post
  - Draft Proposal: "A Human Relations Commission for Metropolitan Nahsville"
  - Report of the Southern Regional Council "Desegregation in Higher Education"
  - King, Martin Luther, Jr. Letter from Birmingham City Jail, distributed by American Friends Service Committee
  - NCRC Workshop: Enrollment of Negro Pupils in Desegregated Schools by Year
  - Report: "Six Years of Public School Desegregation in Nashville and Davidson County," NCRC
  - Stalvey, Lois Mark. "We Moved to an Integrated Neighborhood" Reprint form The Sunday Bulletin Magazine
  - Analysis: "President Kennedy's Civil Rights Bill," Southern Regional Council, Inc.
  - Rustin, Bayard. "The Meaning of Birmingham"
  - Brochure: "Time is Now to March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom"
  - Merton, Thomas. "The Black Revolution: Letters to a White Liberal"
  - Spock, Benjamin. "Children and Discrimination"
  - Gunter, Laurie M. "The Effects of Segregation on Nursing Students" Reprint from Nursing Outlook. Vol. 9.
  - Zoerhiede, Jack D. "But What Will the Neighbors Think?" Forum Series 3 On Controversial Public Issues
  - Nashville Community Relations Council President's Report: Oct. 1963 - May 1965
  - "March and Meaning of Black Power" Presbyterian Life
  - Report on Mississippi Newsletter of Fellowship of Southern Churchmen, Black Mountain, NC
  - 6th National Conference of Friends on Race Relations: 3 Essays, Black Mountain, NC
  - Bagdikian, Ben H. "The Black Immigrants" Saturday Evening Post Reprint
  - St. Laurent, Philip "Cinque and the Amistad Mutiny" The Negro in World History 1968 Flyer: "Genocide" Black Panther Party 1968 Newsletter from Refugees of Resurrection City 1968 Brochure: "A Co-op is Born" Rural Advancement Fund 1/15/68 Feinberg, Lawrence "Boyd Charges 'Politics' on Freeways" Washington Post
  - Flyer: "Genocide" Black Panther Party
  - Newsletter from Refugees of Resurrection City
  - Brochure: "A Co-op is Born" Rural Advancement Fund
  - Feinberg, Lawrence "Boyd Charges 'Politics' on Freeways" Washington Post
  - "Road in Nashville is Still Opposed" New York Times
  - Dilts, James D. "Highway Robbery: Can We Afford It?"
  - MacKenzie, John "Nashville Negroes' Plea Halts Interstate 40 Link" Washington Post
  - "Hosea Williams, Former Chemist, Speaks Out" C&EN
  - "Scientist Bakes Bread for Poor" Science World
  - Mess, Dyer. Letter to the Editor The Tennessean
  - "News and Views" Metro. Public Schools
  - Dillett, Eric S. "Heaven Now or Heaven When?" The Messenger (Quote by James Bevel highlighted), 11-12/68
  - "NAACP Assails Black Militants" Reprint from New York Times
  - Announcement: "Nashville Perspective" Channel 2 TV
  - "But I Read His Book", play Pre-College Players Re: Autobiography of Malcolm X
  - Browning, Al. Book Review of On The Run "The Story of an 18-year Flight from FBI Pursuit" Coalition for Freedom of Parker and Allen
  - Boycott Notice of Shell Products "Stop Apartheid in South Africa; Protect Jobs in U.S.A.
  - Brochure: Join African-American Cultural Alliance with Membership Application
  - Press Release: Davidson County/Nashville Coalition "Fight for Justice Continues"
  - "The Church: A Catalyst for Change in the 1990s "NAACP Invitation and Program for Registration
- Album Program: 1961 6-page Written Program to Record Album "We Shall Overcome," Songs of the "Freedom Riders" and the "Sit-ins", Folkways LP #5591 Bibliography Walton, Frankie S. African Literature in English Fisk University Essays
- Bibliography: Walton, Frankie S. African Literature in English Fisk University
- Essays
  - Fuson, Nelson, "It Happened in 1961"
  - Bevel, James, "A Movement to End Mass Murder"
  - Jones, Lonenzo, "Community Power, Racism and the Church" Chicago Metropolitan Assurance Co.
  - Shannon, Elaine, "Women in Politics"
- Slides: Nelson Fuson Slide Duplication Order List, Kelly Miller Smith Collection
- Poetry
  - Lester, Julius B. "The Death of Justice in Nashville"
  - Lester, Julius B. "A Burial in Nashville"
  - Ayers, Dane. "The Land of Th/"
  - Chan, L. "January 4, 1963"